Vivian G. Brown

Berkeley, CA • vivian.brown@gmail.com

Portfolio: vivianbrown.appspot.com • GitHub: github.com/vbrown608

SUMMARY

Drupal/PHP developer at Quilted cooperative. Designed and built web applications in Python, JavaScript/JQuery/D3, HTML5 and CSS3. Wrote and published widely read research on Agile software development and user experience delivery. Conducted research using applied predictive analysis and machine learning techniques on bioacoustic data.

EDUCATION

Pomona College, Claremont, CA 2007-2011 Bachelor of Arts in Cognitive Science Minor in Computer Science Cum Laude, GPA 3.81/4.00

Undergraduate thesis in machine translation

- Identified features of simple sentences based on models of linguistic complexity
- Working in Java, re-ranked the output of a probabilistic phrase-based translation model using a support vector machine re-ranker to improve machine translation

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Open Disclosure Oakland (opendisclosure.io)

- Volunteer project as part of Code for America's Oakland Brigade
- Visual design, interaction design, and development of interactive visualizations of campaign finance data
- Fully responsive design implemented in CSS, JavaScript, and D3
- Map-based visualization of geospatial data

MetaTicTacToe (metatictactoe.appspot.com)

- Visual design, interaction design, and development of browser-based strategy game
- Backend in Python on Google App Engine, GQL, Google Channel API, webapp2 framework, Jinja2 templating
- Frontend in JavaScript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3
- Implemented adversarial search using negamax algorithm with alpha-beta pruning

CSA Match (code at github.com/vbrown608/csa-match)

- Backend in Python on Google App Engine, GQL, Google Channel API, webapp2 framework, Jinja2 templating
- Map-based visualization of geospatial data using Google Maps JavaScript API v3
- Implemented geospatial search of CSA records using Google Search API

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Developer and Candidate Worker/Owner Quilted (June 2014-present)

- · Web development in Drupal with custom PHP development
- Fully responsive front-end development using JavaScript and Sass
- Lead developer on two client projects
- Major contributor on five client projects, following an Agile process with significant pair programming
- Behavior-driven development using Behat and Selenium and git version control on all projects
- Database experience in MySQL and MongoDB
- Implemented subscription-based payment processing using Stripe API
- Participation in consensus-based decision-making process working towards business co-ownership

IT Researcher/Analyst Forrester Research (October 2012-present)

- Wrote syndicated research on Agile software development, requirements definition, cloud platforms, and predictive analytics tools for senior application development leaders in Fortune 500 IT organizations
- Automated team processes in Visual Basic and JavaScript/Google App Script including integration with Salesforce via OAuth2

- Worked on 3,000+ respondent surveys including survey design, data cuts and analysis, and creation of figures for publication in Adobe Illustrator
- Awarded "Best Research Award" Q3 2012 and "Most Courageous Research Award" Q3 2013
- Promoted to Senior Research Associate after twelve months, then promoted to Researcher after five months

Machine Learning Research Assistant to Dr. Xiaoli Fern, Oregon State University (Summer 2010)

- Working in C++, applied predictive analysis and machine learning techniques to bioacoustic data
- Contributed to a shared code base on a five-person team
- · Collected, read, and summarized research on bioacoustic data analysis with focus on random forest algorithm
- Summarized results in a written report and presented at the Grace Hopper Conference for Women in Computing

Web Administrator Department of Cognitive Science and Linguistics, Pomona College (2010-2011)

- Worked with faculty and staff to update the content and design of department website
- Using HTML and CSS, updated navigation system, restructured faculty profiles, and posted regular updates

Computer Science Teaching Assistant Department of Computer Science, Pomona College (2010-2011)

- TA for "Fundamentals of Computer Science" and "Data Structures" courses
- Facilitated programming labs and held weekly office hours to assist with assignments in Java, C++, and SML